Guide to the Elizabeth L. Eisenstein Papers, 1936-2015
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VII. TEACHING MATERIALS
  - University of Michigan, 1975 (Folder 72.4)
  - University of Michigan, 1975-1981 (Folder 40.6)
  - University of Michigan, 1976 (Folder 40.7)
  - University of Michigan, 1976-1986 (Folder 40.8)
  - University of Michigan, 1977 (Folder 72.5)
  - University of Michigan, 1978 (Folder 40.9)
  - University of Michigan, 1978 (Folder 72.6)
  - University of Michigan, circa 1979 (Folder 40.10)
  - University of Michigan, 1980 (Folder 40.11)
  - Syllabi for courses on the French Revolution, 1968-1981 (Folder 40.12)
  - Miscellaneous bibliographies and syllabi, undated (Folder 40.13)
  - Miscellaneous syllabi and teaching notes, 1973-1977 (Folder 72.7)
- SERIES VIII. ORGANIZATION AND SOCIETY MATERIALS
  - American Antiquarian Society, 1983-1984 (Folder 40.14)
  - American Antiquarian Society, 1984-1985 (Folder 40.15)
  - American Antiquarian Society, 1987-1988 (Folder 40.16)
  - American Historical Association, 1981-1984 (Folder 41.1)
  - American Historical Association. Committee on Committees, 1970-1972 (Folder 41.2)
  - American Historical Association. Committee on International Historical Activities, 1986-1988 (Folder 41.3)
  - American Historical Association. Gershoy Award Committee, 1981 (Folder 41.4)
  - American Historical Association. National History Center, 2004 (Folder 41.5)
  - American Historical Review, 1984-1985 (Folder 41.6)
  - American Historical Review, 1985 (Folder 41.7)
  - American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies, 1970-1974 (Folder 41.8)
  - American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies. Executive Board, 1974-1975 (Folder 41.9)
  - Arthur and Elizabeth Schlesinger Library on the History of Women in America. Advisory Board, 1965-1969 (Folder 41.10)
  - Book History, undated (Folder 41.11)
  - City Museum of Washington, D.C., 1999-2001 (Folder 41.12)
  - D.C. Area French Historians, undated (Folder 41.13)
  - Eighteenth-Century Studies, 1982-1984 (Folder 41.14)
  - Eighteenth-Century Studies, undated (Folder 41.15)
  - Eighteenth-Century Studies, undated (Folder 42.1)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library. Board of Governors, 2001-2008 (Folder 42.2)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library. Board of Governors, 2006-2008 (Folder 42.3)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library. Board of Governors/Search Committee/ Long-Term Fellows, 2001-2007 (Folder 42.4)
  - History of Science, 1983 (Folder 42.5)
  - John Carter Brown Library. National Advisory Council, 1894-1985 (Folder 42.6)
  - Journal of Modern History, 1981 (Folder 42.7)
  - Journal of Modern History, 1983-1984 (Folder 42.8)
  - Journal of Modern History. Editorial Board, 1973-1976 (Folder 42.9)
  - Library of Congress. Center for the Book, 1977-1979 (Folders 42.10-11)
  - Library of Congress. Center for the Book, 1978-1979 (Folder 43.1)
  - Library of Congress. Center for the Book, 1978-1981 (Folder 43.2)
  - Library of Congress. Center for the Book, 1980 (Folder 43.3)
  - Library of Congress. Council of Scholars, 1980-1987 (Folder 43.4)
  - Library of Congress. Council of Scholars, 1981-1985 (Folder 43.5)
  - McArthur Foundation/Mellon Foundation, 1982-2003 (Folder 43.6)
  - Oxford University Press, 2005 (Folder 43.7)
  - Past America 1492 Project. Advisory Board, 1984-1991 (Folder 43.8)
  - Penn State Press, 1997 (Folder 43.9)
  - Renaissance Society of America, 1985-1987 (Folder 43.10)
  - Syracuse University Press, undated (Folder 43.11)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1997 (Folder 43.12)
  - [University of Toronto Press?], circa 1982 (Folder 72.8)
  - Vassar College. Department of History. Visiting Committee, undated (Folder 43.13)
  - Wilson Center, 1983-1990 (Folder 43.14)
  - Wilson Center, 1984-1989 (Folder 43.15)
- SERIES IX. COLLEAGUES PAPERS
  - Addison, Bland, Jr., 1980-1981 (Folder 44.1)
  - Addison, Bland, Jr., 1993 (Folder 44.2)
  - Ahern, John, 1982-1988 (Folder 44.3)
  - Ahrens, Rudiger, 1989 (Folder 44.4)
  - Anninger, Anne, circa 1982 (Folder 44.5)
  - Arnheim, Rudolf, circa 1962 (Folder 72.9)
  - Aston, Margaret, circa 1977 (Folder 44.6)
  - Baker, Keith, 1980-1984 (Folder 44.7)
  - Baker, Keith, 1980-1988 (Folders 44.8-9)
  - Baker, Keith, circa 1992 (Folder 44.10)
  - Baker, Keith, Jack Censer, undated (Folder 44.11)
  - Barker, Nicholas, circa 1983 (Folder 44.12)
  - Bell, David, 1994-1998 (Folder 44.13)
  - Bell-Villada, Gene H., 1987 (Folder 44.14)
  - Bien, David D., circa 1978 (Folder 44.15)
  - Birn, Raymond, circa 1975-1978 (Folder 44.16)
  - Birn, Raymond, circa 1987 (Folder 44.17)
  - Birn, Raymond, 1991-1992 (Folder 44.18)
  - Blair, Ann, 2001-2010 (Folder 45.1)
  - Blair, Ann, 2006 (Folder 45.2)
  - Bosman, Anston, circa 2004 (Folder 45.3)
  - Brann, Noel L., 1979-1998 (Folder 45.4)
  - Brooks, Dalton, undated (Folder 45.5)
  - Brown, Barbara Traxler, 1987 (Folder 45.6)
  - Bryant, Lawrence, 1989 (Folder 45.7)
  - Capraro, Rocco L., 1983-1985 (Folder 45.8)
  - Carrithers, Gale H., Jr., circa 1989 (Folder 45.9)
  - Castle, Terry, circa 1994 (Folder 45.10)
  - Cavanaugh, Gerald, J., circa 1975 (Folder 45.11)
  - Censer, Jack, circa 2013 (Folder 45.12)
  - Censer, Jack, undated (Folder 45.13)
  - Chandler, Eric V., 1992-1995 (Folder 45.14)
  - Chartier, Roger, circa 1982 (Folder 45.15)
  - Chartier, Roger, 2007 (Folder 45.16)
  - Clouatre, Dallas L., 1984 (Folder 45.17)
  - Colton, Joel, circa 1981 (Folder 45.18)
  - Condren, Conal, 1986 (Folder 45.19)
  - Darnton, Robert, circa 1976-circa 1980 (Folder 45.20)
  - Daston, Lorraine J., 1981 (Folder 46.1)
  - Davis, Natalie Zemon, circa 1965-circa 1973 (Folders 46.2-3)
  - Davis, Natalie Zemon, circa 1991 (Folder 46.4)
  - DeLacy, Margaret, circa 2005 (Folder 46.5)
  - De la Mare, Albinia, circa 1971-1978 (Folder 72.10)
  - De Maria, Robert, Jr., 1989-circa 1992 (Folder 46.6)
  - Dooley, Brendan, circa 1989 (Folder 46.7)
  - Downing, Donn, 2003 (Folder 46.8)
  - During, Simon, 1988 (Folder 46.9)
  - Euler, Carrie, circa 2004 (Folder 46.10)
  - Fabian, Bernhard, circa 1976 (Folder 46.11)
  - Farrell, Thomas J., 2011 (Folder 47.1)
  - Ferguson, Charles A., circa 1991 (Folder 47.2)
  - Fingarette, Herbert, 1983 (Folder 47.3)
  - Franceschini, Adriano, 1983 (Folder 47.4)
  - Freedman, Joseph S., 1986 (Folder 47.5)
  - Gilmore, Myron P., 1969-1975 (Folder 47.6)
  - Gilreath, James, 1990 (Folder 47.7)
  - Goldgar, Anne, 1987-1989 (Folder 47.8)
  - Goldie, Mark, 1980-circa 1987 (Folder 47.9)
  - Goldstone, Jack A., Jeremy D. Popkin, 1992-1993 (Folder 47.10)
  - Goodman, Dena, circa 1986 (Folder 47.11)
  - Goodman, Dena, 1993 (Folder 47.21)
  - Gordon, Daniel, 1993 (Folder 47.13)
  - Goodman, Michael John, 2001 (Folder 47.14)
  - Green, Ian, 1985-1986 (Folder 47.15)
  - Greenblatt, Stephen, circa 2011 (Folder 47.16)
  - Grendler, Paul F., 1983 (Folder 47.17)
  - Grimsted, Patricia Kennedy, 1970 (Folder 47.18)
  - Gross, Robert A., 1998 (Folder 48.1)
  - Gross, Robert A., circa 2008 (Folder 48.2)
  - Guilhaumou, Jacques, 1987 (Folder 48.3)
  - Gumbrecht, Hans Ulrich, undated (Folder 48.4)
  - Gunn, J. A., circa 1985 (Folder 48.5)
  - Guss, David M., 1988 (Folder 48.6)
  - Haakonssen, Knud, 1993 (Folder 48.7)
  - Haber, Francis C., circa 1971 (Folder 48.8)
  - Hall, David D., circa 1984 (Folder 48.9)
  - Halporn, Barbara, circa 2002 (Folder 48.10)
  - Hannaway, Owen, circa 1986 (Folder 48.11)
  - Harrold, Nicola, 1999 (Folder 48.12)
  - Hartwick, John M., 1985 (Folder 48.13)
  - Harvey, John L., 2014 (Folder 48.14)
  - Hesse, Carla, 1987 (Folder 48.15)
  - Hirschman, Albert O., 1983 (Folder 48.16)
  - Hoffmann, Richard C., circa 1986 (Folder 48.17)
  - Horowitz, Irving Lewis, 1984 (Folder 48.18)
  - Hoskin, Keith, 1983-1985 (Folder 49.1)
  - Hunt, Arnold, 2007 (Folder 49.2)
  - Hunt, Lynn, circa 1979-2014 (Folders 49.3-4)
  - Hunt, Lynn, circa 1982 (Folder 49.5)
  - Hutton, Patrick H., 1994 (Folder 49.6)
  - Johns, Adrian, 1991 (Folder 49.7)
  - Kaestle, Carl F., 1992 (Folder 49.8)
  - Kafker, Frank A., 1963-1981 (Folders 49.9-10)
  - Kaiser, Thomas E., 1980-1989 (Folder 49.11)
  - Katsch, Ethan, 1986 (Folder 49.12)
  - Kelly, Ann, circa 1995 (Folder 49.13)
  - Kennedy, Emmet, circa 2012 (Folder 49.14)
  - Kingdon, Robert, circa 1977 (Folder 49.15)
  - Klaits, Joseph, undated (Folder 49.16)
  - Klauber, Martin I., 1990 (Folder 49.17)
  - Koenigsberger, Dorothy, circa 1992 (Folder 49.18)
  - Kornicki, Peter, 1988 (Folder 49.19)
  - Kronick, David A., 1980 (Folder 49.20)
  - Latour, Bruno, 1983 (Folder 50.1)
  - La Vopa, Tony, 1990-1991 (Folder 50.2)
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1982-1983 (Folder 72.11)
  - Leeds, Eric J., 1983 (Folder 50.3)
  - Levy, Fritz J., circa 1986 (Folder 50.4)
  - Lingo, Alison C., 1993 (Folder 50.5)
  - Loewenstein, Joseph F., 1987 (Folder 50.6)
  - Lowry, Martin, circa 1989 (Folder 50.7)
  - Lusebrink, Hans-Jurgen, 1988-1990 (Folders 50.8-9)
  - Lydgate, Barry, 1974-1981 (Folder 50.10)
  - MacCulloch, Diarmid, 2002 (Folder 50.11)
  - Margerison, Kenneth, 1989-1992 (Folder 50.12)
  - Marker, Gary J., 1979-1985 (Folder 50.13)
  - Marks, Richard B., 1975-1977 (Folder 51.1)
  - Marotti, Arthur F., undated (Folder 51.2)
  - Martin, J. W., circa 1981 (Folder 51.3)
  - Maza, Sara, 1986-1987 (Folder 51.4)
  - McArthur, Tom, circa 1987 (Folder 51.5)
  - McConica, James, circa 1974 (Folder 51.6)
  - McCusker, John J., 2006 (Folder 51.7)
  - McDowell, Paula, 2007 (Folder 51.8)
  - McLaughlin, Mary Martin, circa 1975 (Folder 51.9)
  - Mehl, James, 1976 (Folder 51.10)
  - Merton, Robert K., circa 1971 (Folder 51.11)
  - Meyerowitz, Joshua, 1984-1985 (Folder 51.12)
  - Miethke, Jurge, 1983 (Folder 51.13)
  - Miner, Ear, 1979-1981 (Folder 51.14)
  - Moote, A. Lloyd, Lawrence M. Bryant, undated (Folder 51.15)
  - Moran, Daniel J., 1980 (Folder 51.16)
  - Morton, Brian N., 1971 (Folder 51.17)
  - Mueller, Milton, 1986 (Folder 51.18)
  - Neely, Sylvia, 1980 (Folder 51.19)
  - Noakes, Susan, circa 1977 (Folder 51.20)
  - Olson, David R., 1986 (Folder 51.21)
  - Olson, David R., circa 1993 (Folder 52.1)
  - Ong, Walter J., 1972-circa 1979 (Folder 52.2)
  - Orihel, Michelle, 2005-2013 (Folder 52.3)
  - Otte, Michael, undated (Folder 52.4)
  - Pallares-Burke, Maria Lucia, 1997 (Folder 52.5)
  - Palmer, R. R., J. W. Schultz Nordholt, circa 1980 (Folder 52.6)
  - Parshall, Peter, 2013 (Folder 52.7)
  - Pedley, Mary Sponberg, 1979 (Folder 52.8)
  - Peckinson, Henry J., 1986 (Folder 52.9)
  - Peters, Julie Stone, 1995 (Folder 52.10)
  - Pocock, John, circa 1980 (Folder 52.11)
  - Popkin, Jeremy, 1978-1987 (Folder 52.12)
  - Popkin, Jeremy, 1978-2000 (Folders 52.13-14)
  - Popkin, Jeremy, 1978-2000 (Folder 53.1)
  - Popkin, Jeremy, circa 1993 (Folder 53.2)
  - Ranum, Orest, circa 1980 (Folder 53.3)
  - Ranum, Orest, Robert A. Schneider, 1990-1991 (Folder 53.4)
  - Ramsey, Matthew, 1982 (Folder 53.5)
  - Reeds, Karen, 1977-1983 (Folder 53.6)
  - Richler, Melvin, circa 2003 (Folder 53.7)
  - Riddle, J., 1970 (Folder 53.8)
  - Robertson, Douglas S., 1986 (Folder 53.9)
  - Roelker, Nancy Lyman, 1986 (Folder 53.10)
  - Rosaldo, Renato, undated (Folder 53.11)
  - Rosen, Edward, 1965 (Folder 53.12)
  - Rosen, Jay, 1986 (Folder 53.13)
  - Rosenfield, Leonora Cohen, circa 1978 (Folder 53.14)
  - Roth, Michael S., 1986 (Folder 53.15)
  - Rothkrug, Lionel, Isser Wolock, undated (Folder 53.16)
  - Runzo, Jean, 1979 (Folder 53.17)
  - Ryan, Alan, undated (Folder 53.18)
  - Saenger, Paul, 1981-circa 1984 (Folder 54.1)
  - Sahlins, Peter, circa 1990 (Folder 54.2)
  - Sawyer, Jeffrey K., circa 1988 (Folder 72.12)
  - Schalk, David L., 2004-2005 (Folder 54.3)
  - Schoeck, Richard J., circa 1972 (Folder 54.5)
  - Schoeck, Richard J., 1995-1996 (Folder 54.6)
  - Schudson, Michael, 1992-1993 (Folder 54.7)
  - Schutte, Anne Jacobson, circa 1976 (Folder 54.8)
  - Schwoerer, Lois, 1977 (Folder 54.9)
  - Schwoerer, Lois, circa 1994 (Folder 54.10)
  - Shackleton, Robert, circa 1977 (Folder 54.11)
  - Shelby, Lon R., 1970-1974 (Folder 54.12)
  - Sher, Richard B., 2000-circa 2001 (Folder 54.13)
  - Sher, Richard B., undated (Folder 54.14)
  - Sherman, William H., 2002 (Folder 54.15)
  - Siegel, Jerrold, circa 1981 (Folder 54.16)
  - Slavine, Arthur J., 1983 (Folder 54.17)
  - Smith, Bonnie G., undated (Folder 54.18)
  - Solomon, Howard M., circa 1973 (Folder 55.1)
  - Spitzer, Alan B., circa 1986-1994 (Folder 55.2)
  - Statelmajer, Ingrid I., 2012 (Folder 55.3)
  - Steneck, Nicholas H., circa 1981 (Folder 55.4)
  - Steneck, Nicholas H., undated (Folder 55.5)
  - Stoker, David, 2003 (Folder 55.6)
  - Tackett, Tim, 1993-1994 (Folder 55.7)
  - Tannen, Deborah, 1981 (Folder 55.8)
  - Van Dorsten, Jan A., 1980-1985 (Folder 55.9)
  - Van Kley, Dale K., 1990 (Folder 55.10)
  - Vittu, Jean-Pierre, 1990 (Folder 72.13)
  - Wall-Randell, Sarah, 2005 (Folder 55.11)
  - Walley, David G., 2004 (Folder 55.12)
  - Walsham, Alexandria, Alison Shell, circa 2002 (Folder 55.13)
  - Walters, Alice, 1989 (Folder 55.14)
  - Waquet, Francoise, 1936-1937 (Folder 55.15)
  - Warner, D. J., undated (Folder 55.16)
  - Watts, Ian, 1983 (Folder 55.17)
  - Werking, Richard Hume, 2005 (Folder 55.18)
  - Westman, Robert S., circa 1972 (Folder 55.19)
  - Westman, Robert S., 1973-1978 (Folder 55.20)
  - Westman, Robert S., 2006 (Folder 55.21)
  - Westman, Robert S., 2006-2011 (Folder 56.1)
  - Wheeler, Tom, 2013 (Folder 56.2)
  - Williamson, Arthur, 2007 (Folder 56.3)
  - Wilson, Curtis, 1974 (Folder 56.4)
  - Withee, Diana, circa 1989 (Folder 56.5)
  - Woodbridge, John D., 1984 (Folder 56.6)
  - Yardeni, Myriam, circa 1984 (Folder 56.7)
  - Zagorin, Perez, 2002-2007 (Folder 56.8)
  - Student Curriculum Committee (Folder 56.9)
  - Zaret, David, 1989-2000 (Folder 56.10)
- SERIES X. TRAVEL MATERIALS
  - Arizona - Tuscon, Tempe, 1995 (Folder 56.11)
  - Bermuda, 1995-2007 (Folder 56.12)
  - Cambridge, MA, undated (Folder 56.13)
  - England - London, Oxford, 1990-1997 (Folder 57.1)
  - England, France, Switzerland, 1967-1975 (Folder 57.2)
  - Indianapolis, IN, 2006 (Folder 57.3)
  - Israel, undated (Folder 57.4)
  - Jackson, WY, 2001 (Folder 57.5)
  - London, England; Oslo, Norway, 1997, 2003 (Folder 57.6)
  - London/Oxford, England; Oslo, Norway, 1997 (Folder 72.14)
  - New York State - Adirondacks, circa 1999-2006 (Folder 57.7)
  - Old itineraries - Italy, Spain, 1967-1985 (Folder 57.8)
  - Portland, OR, 2006 (Folder 57.9)
  - Portland, OR, undated (Folder 57.10)
  - Portland, OR; Vancouver, WA, 2014 (Folder 57.11)
  - San Diego, CA, undated (Folder 57.12)
  - Santa Fe, NM, 2003 (Folder 57.13)
  - Tuscon, AZ, 2008-2014 (Folder 57.14)
  - Virginia - Charlottesville, Williamsburg, undated (Folder 57.15)
  - Miscellaneous travel materials, undated (Folder 57.16)
- SERIES XI. SUBJECT FILES
  - 18th-century press, undated (Folder 57.17)
  - 18th-century reading public, undated (Folder 57.18)
  - Adventure and Art: Odyssey of the Book, circa 1972 (Folder 72.15)
  - Agent of Change: Print Culture Studies after Elizabeth Eisenstein, 2007 (Folder 57.19)
  - Alexandrian Library, 2006 (Folder 58.1)
  - American and Rench revolutions - comparisons, 2011 (Folder 58.2)
  - American Historical Association - David Abraham case, 1984-1985 (Folder 58.3)
  - American Historical Association - party, 1982 (Folder 58.4)
  - American University Library, 2014 (Folder 58.5)
  - American University - library; resignation from faculty, 1973-1976 (Folder 72.16)
  - Apartments - Paris, France, 1989-1999 (Folder 58.6)
  - Arabic printing - Natalie Zemon Davis, Gerald Holton, David Landes, 1993-2006 (Folder 58.7)
  - Areopagitica, circa 1993 (Folder 58.8)
  - Arizona, 2007-2008 (Folder 58.9)
  - Bangura, Salamatu, 2012-2014 (Folder 58.10)
  - Baron, Sabrina Alcorn, 1999 (Folder 58.11)
  - Blake, William, undated (Folder 58.12)
  - Book history quotations, 2008 (Folder 58.13)
  - Book trades and reading in antebellum New England, 1996-1997 (Folder 58.14)
  - Book trades and reading, bibliographies, 1973-2003 (Folder 58.15)
  - Brahe, Tycho, 1961-1973 (Folder 58.16)
  - British fiction, 2008 (Folder 58.17)
  - Buchtel, John, 1999 (Folder 58.18)
  - Burke, Edmund, 2012 (Folder 58.19)
  - Cambridge University Press - 400th anniversary, 1984 (Folder 72.17)
  - Communications and propaganda, circa 1973-circa 1980 (Folder 58.20)
  - Copenhaver [Brian P.] on Vergil, 2008 (Folder 58.21)
  - Darnton, Robert, 1981-1982 (Folder 58.22)
  - Darnton, Robert, 1992-1997 (Folder 59.1)
  - Davis, Natalie Zemon, 1985-2003 (Folder 59.2)
  - De Simone, Daniel, 2013 (Folder 59.3)
  - Deghaiss, Pauline, 2012-2014 (Folder 59.4)
  - Democratic Enlightenment, 2014 (Folder 59.5)
  - Domestic employees, 1962-1965 (Folder 59.6)
  - Donne, John, 1985-circa 1999 (Folder 59.7)
  - Driver, Elizabeth, 1999 (Folder 59.8)
  - Dutch travel books, circa 2009 (Folder 59.9)
  - Editorial assistance, 2008; [applications and curriculum vitae] (Folder 59.10)
  - Eisenstein, Elizabeth, 2003-2005; [miscellaneous reviews of books by, biographical essay] (Folder 59.11)
  - Eisenstein, John, 1969-2011 (Folder 59.12)
  - Eisenstein, Julian, 2006 (Folder 59.13)
  - Eisenstein, Julian, 2010-2015 (Folder 59.14)
  - Eisenstein family, 2010-2013; [holiday newsletters] (Folder 59.15)
  - Encyclopedie, circa 2005 (Folder 59.16)
  - England - 17th-18th century, undated (Folder 60.1)
  - England - 18th century, undated (Folder 60.2)
  - England - 19th century, undated (Folder 60.3)
  - Engravings in books, 2005 (Folder 60.4)
  - Ersatz controversy and critiques, 2001 (Folder 60.5)
  - An Essay on Writing and the Art and Mystery of Printing, 2005 (Folder 60.6)
  - Evalyn Clark Memorial - Vassar College, 2001 (Folder 60.7)
  - Evalyn Clark Memorial - Vassar College, 2002 (Folder 60.8)
  - Fortunes of Fables in the Eighteenth Century - ASECS Seminary proposal, 1993 (Folder 60.9)
  - Foxe, John, circa 1999-circa 2004 (Folder 60.10)
  - French education, undated (Folder 60.11)
  - France, 18th century - journalism and the press, undated (Folder 60.12)
  - French Revolution - journalism, undated (Folder 60.13)
  - French Revolution - music, songs, theater, undated (Folder 60.14)
  - French Revolutionary songs, undated (Folder 60.15)
  - Future of print - interviews, 2009-2010 (Folder 60.16)
  - Gissing, George, 2008 (Folder 60.17)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1982-1983 (Folder 61.1)
  - Gutenberg - 400th anniversary, undated (Folder 61.2)
  - Gutenberg - anniversaries/commemorations, undated (Folder 61.3)
  - Henricksen, Erin, 1999 (Folder 61.4)
  - Hetland, Per, undated (Folder 61.5)
  - History and post-modernism, 1990-1991 (Folder 61.6)
  - History of printing - South Asia, Southeast Asia, 2000 (Folder 61.7)
  - History of reading and reader reception, undated (Folder 61.8)
  - History of science, undated (Folder 61.9)
  - History of the book, printing, publishing, and news media in America, undated (Folder 61.10)
  - Home health care, 2014 (Folder 61.11)
  - Hume, David, undated (Folder 61.12)
  - "Image d'Epinal,", 1997 (Folder 61.13)
  - "The Enlightenment," by Anthony Padgen, 2013; [review by Jonathan Israel, letter to editor by Eisenstein] (Folder 61.14)
  - John Eisenstein Fellowships - St. Alban's School, circa 1980-2012 (Folder 61.15)
  - Johns, Adrian, circa 1999-2000 (Folder 61.16)
  - Johns, Adrian, circa 1999 (Folder 72.18)
  - Kennedy, Emmet, 1984 (Folder 62.1)
  - Kindle, Google - books and digital technology, undated (Folder 62.2)
  - Krivatsy, Nati H., 1979 (Folder 62.3)
  - Language, speech, undated (Folder 62.4)
  - "Le Garage" - Paris, France, circa 1990-1992 (Folder 62.5)
  - L'Estrange, Robert, Sir, 2009 (Folder 62.6)
  - Lewisohn, Adolph, 2011-2012 (Folder 72.19)
  - Lindquist, Eric, 1999 (Folder 62.7)
  - Literacy/illiteracy - Middle Ages, circa 1985 (Folder 62.8)
  - Long, Pamela O., 2014 (Folder 62.9)
  - Marvell, Andrew - "The Rehearsal Transpos'd,", undated (Folder 62.10)
  - McCune, John F., 1995-2007 (Folder 62.11)
  - McCune, John F. - retirement, 1994-2001 (Folder 62.12)
  - McLeod, Jane, 1986 (Folder 62.13)
  - Mentz, Steven, 1999 (Folder 62.14)
  - Moore, Roger, 1999 (Folder 62.15)
  - Music printing, 1981-1986 (Folder 62.16)
  - National Coalition of Independent Scholars, 1993-1995 (Folder 62.17)
  - New Literacy - Harvard program, 1982 (Folder 62.18)
  - Ong, Walter J., circa 1970-2005 (Folder 62.19)
  - Oral literature and silent reading, undated (Folder 62.20)
  - Oxford, England - visits, 1999-2002 (Folder 62.21)
  - Pamphlets - England, France, undated (Folder 63.1)
  - Periodization - Renaissance/Early Modern, circa 1996-circa 2007 (Folder 63.2)
  - Perspectives on Political Reporting seminar, 1992 (Folder 63.3)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1985-1988 (Folder 63.4)
  - Phonograph records, 2000 (Folder 63.5)
  - Print culture - bibliographies, 2001 (Folder 63.6)
  - Printed sermons, 2006 (Folder 63.7)
  - Printing - early reactions to, circa 1972 (Folder 72.20)
  - Printing and bookselling in colonial Virginia, 1996-2005 (Folder 63.8)
  - Printing history - comparative, 1987-2007 (Folder 63.9)
  - Printing in the Islamic world, circa 2002-2008 (Folder 63.10)
  - Printing in the Islamic world, undated (Folder 63.11)
  - Printing, knowledge, and public opinion in America, undated (Folder 63.12)
  - Printing, publishing, reading - 19th century, undated (Folder 63.13)
  - Publishers, public opinion - 19th-century France, circa 2007 (Folder 63.14)
  - Pulpit and press, circa 1984 (Folder 63.15)
  - Rosary, 2007 (Folder 63.16)
  - Royal Historical Society, 2014-2015 (Folder 63.17)
  - Science - France, undated (Folder 63.18)
  - Shevlin, Eleanor, 1999 (Folder 63.19)
  - Society for French Historical Studies, 1969-1970 (Folder 63.20)
  - A Tale of a Tube - paratexts, undated (Folder 64.1)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, circa 1976 (Folder 64.2)
  - Tresors de la Biblioteque National de France - Library of Congress exhibit, 1995 (Folder 64.3)
  - United States - Early Republic, undated (Folder 64.4)
  - Typewriters, 1988-1989 (Folder 64.5)
  - Typographic [poem], undated (Folder 64.6)
  - University of Michigan, 2010-2011 (Folder 64.7)
  - University of Michigan - health claims, 1975-2008 (Folder 64.8)
  - Uzanne, Octave, 1995-2009 (Folder 64.9)
  - Vassar College, 1986-2015 (Folders 64.10-11)
  - Vassar College, 1991-2009 (Folder 64.12)
  - Vassar College - Class of 1945-44 50th reunion, 1992-1995 (Folder 64.13)
  - Vassar College - Class of 1945-44 50th reunion, 2000 (Folders 65.1-2)
  - Vassar College - Class of 1945-44 50th reunion gift, 1992-1994 (Folder 65.3)
  - Venice - Index of Prohibited Books, undated (Folder 65.4)
  - Waverly novels, undated (Folder 65.5)
  - Women's studies - women historians, early-modern women, 1958-1973 (Folder 65.6)
  - Woolf, Virginia, 2008 (Folder 65.7)
  - Wordsworth, William, circa 2007 (Folder 65.8)
- SERIES XII. PRINTED MATERIALS
  - Agent of Change: Print Culture Studies After Elizabeth L. Eisenstein, undated; [book prospectus] (Folder 65.9)
  - Badinter, Elisabeth, undated (Folder 65.10)
  - Baron, Sabrina, undated (Folder 65.11)
  - Berkvens-Stenelinck, Christiane, undated (Folder 65.12)
  - Bibliographies, undated (Folder 65.13)
  - Blair, Ann, Peter Stallybrass, 2014 (Folder 65.14)
  - Calendar, 1993 (Folder 65.15)
  - Chronologies, undated (Folder 65.16)
  - Curti lecture #1 - offprints, undated (Folder 65.17)
  - Dailey, Barbara Ritter, John McCucsker, circa 1981 (Folder 65.18)
  - Divine Art/Infgernal Machine, 1999; [lecture brochure] (Folder 65.19)
  - Fajn, Max, undated (Folder 66.1)
  - The First Hundred Years of Printing, undated; [poster] (Folder 66.2)
  - Fletcher, Andrew, undated (Folder 66.3)
  - Gopnik, Adam, 2011 (Folder 66.4)
  - Guilhamon, Jacques, 1987 (Folder 66.5)
  - Hudson, Nicholas, circa 2002; [review: Challenging Eisenstein: Recent Studies in Print Culture] (Folder 66.6)
  - In Memory of Elizabeth Lewisohn Eisenstein ..., 2016 (Folder 66.7)
  - Interview questions [for Elizabeth Eisenstein], 2004 (Folder 66.8)